AIDAR NUGMANOV

github.com/nugmanoff • linkedin.com/in/nugmanoff • a.nugmanoff@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Since **sophomore** year I have been Mobile Developer (iOS, React Native) at 021labs, company started by **Princeton & CMU** grads, while maintaining **GPA 3.96/4.0** in my university. I was part of one of the most successful e-commerce product team in country (accumulate **1M+ MAU** of all products, **100M \$+ turnover**) and helped to increase App User Retention **6x**, reach **99%** crash-free sessions. In over 3 years I mentored **80+ people** on iOS development and Software Engineering (being Teaching Assistant, Mentor at bootcamp and Founder of my own Mentoring Program).

EDUCATION

SULEYMAN DEMIREL UNIVERSITY

Almaty, Kazakhstan

Bachelor of Computer Science (GPA: 3.9/4.0)

Sep 2016 - Expected May 2020

Coursework: Math for CSc, Probability Statistics, Discrete Mathematics, Graph Theory, Advanced Algorithms, Automata Theory **Honors and Awards:** Presidential Scholarship, 1st place HERE.com Hackathon, 1st place Senim.kz Hackathon (Augmented Reality)

KAZAKH-TURKISH HIGH SCHOOL

Almaty, Kazakhstan Sep 2011 - May 2016

High School Diploma (GPA: 5.0/5.0)

Awards and Certificates: "Golden Sign" of academic excellence; GPA 5.0/5.0; IELTS 8.0; SAT 1490/1600

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

AZIMUT LABS Almaty, Kazakhstan

iOS Developer

Feb 2020 - Present

• Alabs is a company that is oriented at developing complicated highload systems and applications. Portfolio: iOS applications for egov.kz (Electronic Government of Republic of Kazakhstan), post.kz (Kazakhstan National Postal Service)

ARBUZ.KZ

iOS Developer

Almaty, Kazakhstan

Jan 2019 - Feb 2020

- Working on Product Development team with demonstrated history of launching products with over 1M MAU
- 6x increase in User Retention
- Top5 of local App Store Food Drink category
- Integrated Push Notifications, Universal (Deep) Links, third-party Analytics (App Metrica, Firebase), Payment services (CloudPayments)

NFACTORIAL INCUBATOR
Almaty, Kazakhstan

iOS Mentor (employee no.2)

Jun 2018 - Aug 2018

- nFactorial Incubator is the largest app development bootcamp in Central Asia. The results from 4 summers ('15-'18) launched 300+ mobile apps, graduated 400+ mobile developers.
- Mentored group of 35 students on iOS Development
- Designed syllabus and prepared lectures study materials on various topics (Swift, UIKit basics, OOP, POP, Networking, Clean Code, SOLID and etc.)

ZEROTOONELABSAlmaty, Kazakhstan *Mobile Developer*Sep 2017 - Aug 2018

- Developed 4 mobile applications for various projects using iOS SDK React Native (Typescript, Redux, MobX)
- Incorporated Git Flow App Center for CI/CD into development process
- Wrote UI/Unit tests for resting React components (Jest, Enzyme)
- Sketched mobile application designs, user flows, mockups wireframes using Sketch

NFACTORIAL INCUBATOR

iOS Intern

Almaty, Kazakhstan

Jun 2017 - Aug 2017

- Developed 3 iOS applications, 2 of them got ranked top 20 out of 100+ by the end of the program
- Ranked Top1 among 70 students on interval testing on Swift iOS SDK knowledge
- Developed Zheti Söz (DuoLingo analog for Kazakhstani market) Repo Hunt (Github trending repositories)

PROJECTS

REPO HUNT

- iOS application for tracking trending GitHub repositories, 3000 downloads, 600 PH upvotes
- Developed handy Today-wdiget for retrieving most popular repo based on user's behavior
- Implemented Force Touch preview for README's with Github-flavored Markdwon support Built backend application using Ruby + Sinatra for retrieving filtering trending repos

SKILLS

- Proficient with: Swift, Java, Javascript, Typescript
- Prior experience: C++ Ruby
- Other: iOS SDK, Git, Git Flow, React Native, Node.js, Next.js, Jira, CI/CD, Fastlane, AppCenter, Bitrise, Firebase, Yandex Metrica, OAuth